The example of the WHERE clause we have seen uses
precise criteria to filter records down to what we
want within a query. Sometimes though, we may not
know the exact spelling of the criteria for which
we are looking. In these situations, a LIKE clause
added to a WHERE clause allows us to use wildcards
to get approximate matches for criteria. For this
query, instead of using an exact match for the
city criteria, let's say we are not sure of the
city name but that it starts with the letters
LO. I will adjust the City criterion to first
change the equals sign to the keyword LIKE.
Then, I will change Los Angeles to LO%. The
percent symbol (%) is a wildcard that means
any number of characters. The criterion
now basically reads this way: The city
must start with the letters LO but can have
anything after it. I will execute this query,
and we see that we have about 600 records and
multiple cities that start with the letters LO
Let's see what happens if we add a percent symbol
in front of the L and then execute this again.
We are now over 1500 records. The reason is that
the criteria now reads: We want to see any city
with the letters LO in the name, no matter
what is in front of the LO or after the LO.